

Portfolio

julia-santi.vercel.app

ABOUT

I am a Software Engineer with over 5 years of experience. I'm specialize in Frontend with React, Javascript and Typescript. My backend skills lies in Python (Fast API) and Node.js. I really enjoy Clean Code, team work, and continuous learning. In addition to that, I have contributed to the Data Science community through the publication of papers, with a focus on game mining and climate change prediction.

Front-end

React

React Native



styled-components 📆 Typescript



Highcharts



Sass



CSS

Cypress

Jest

Back-end

○ Node.is

MySQL

PostgreSQL

Ruby on Rails

Python - FastAPI

Data Science

R R

Python

FLUENT LANGUAGES

- Enalish
- Portuguese

CONTACT:

E-mail: julia.gs.acosta@gmail.com

Github: github.com/gsajulia

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/julia-

gabriela-santi-acosta

JÚLIA ACOSTA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FullStack and Senior Frontend Developer



- Leading frontend development with React, Typescript and styled-components.
- Backend contributions in Python with FastAPI
- · Collaborating closely with the Project Manager and Design team to align development efforts with project objectives
- Mentoring Junior developers
- ChatGPT API / Parser PDF / AWS (S3)

Software Engineer



Fetchly Labs | Sep 2021 - Jan 2023

- · New features and fix bugs using React, React Native, Ruby on Rails, styled-components and MapBox aligning with Figma design specifications
- · Collaborated closely with the Project Manager, QA, and Design teams to ensure a cohesive development process
- · Managed the release cycles for both web and app platforms (Android/IOS)
- Mentoring junior developers
- Conducted technical interviews for new developers



Frontend Developer S Drakkar | Mar 2020 - Jul 2021

- Lead software team, aligning strategies with the CEO.
- · Managed developers' task progress.
- Implemented new features and bug fixes using React and styled-components for a KPI-based system.

Frontend Developer



COWMED Oct 2018 - Oct 2019

(Internship)

- · Maintain a Cows monitoring system using React and Highcharts
- Migrating JQuery code to new React components

EDUCATION

Universidade de São Paulo (USP)

Data Science | 2023 - Present

Universidade Federal de Santa Maria (UFSM)

Graduate | Information Systems | 2017 - 2022

VOLUNTEER

ADPList | Mar 2023 - Oct 2023

Passionate about mentoring, I provide guidance on career development, upskilling the technologies, and mock interviews.